Hi, I'm Dominic Waite, founder of
CaribNexus AI and this is CaribBooks.
CaribBooks is an AI bookkeeper
that lives entirely in WhatsApp.
We built CaribBooks because we've noticed
a general problem with bookkeeping
services not only within Jamaica but
the wider Caribbean for where MSMEs are
concerned and accounting practices.
MSME stands for micro, small,
medium-sized enterprises.
For these types of companies,
most of them do not have an internal system
of recording their transactions that is
always reliable, that is
always available to them 24-7,
that can adequately take in all of
their transactions wherever they are.
As for an accounting practice,
we've realised that they spend a
lot of time posting transactions,
doing bookkeeping,
valuable time that they could spend on
higher value work such as advisory services
where tax planning is concerned and
even cases of financial reporting.
Without anything further to
say, as an introduction,
I'm going to head into how exactly CaribBooks
could work for the typical MSME through WhatsApp.
First things first, I can be able
to specify a transaction via text.
What I can do is to say,
for example, Hi CB,
I have received a payment
for an AI automation service.
Automation service for the amount
of, let us specify an amount,
$180,000 JMD amount was
received via NCB transfer.
Additionally, I can say the service was
for an AI marketing system that was built.
Sending this as a message to CB, CB
will be able to see the message,
acknowledge it and post the transaction.
There we go, so CB posted, debited NCB
and credited custom development revenue.
What I can do next is to attach a receipt.
This is a receipt of things that I've
purchased via cash from my office.
I can send this as a message to CB,
CB will be able to see the receipt,
acknowledge it and post the
transaction accordingly.
Let us wait for that.
There we go, it acknowledged
via receipt, posted,
made a debit entry to office
supplies, credited cash on hand.
The next thing that I can do is to specify a
transaction via voice note or a voice message.
What I can do is to
specifically say, hey CB,
so I've just recently made a payment to one
of my employees for their bi-weekly salary.
So the total was for the
amount of $52,000 JMD.
The amount was made via
an NCB ACH transfer.
Sending this across to CB,
CB will be able to hear the voice note and
acknowledge accordingly and post the transaction.
Give it some time.
As you can see, it posted the transaction,
debited miscellaneous expense, credited NCB.
It realised that there wasn't any dedicated wages
or salaries accounts in the chart of accounts.
If it is a case that we want to make
a wages or salaries expense account,
the accounting firm,
if they're using this solution as a white
label solution for the MSMEs they serve,
they can create in the chart of accounts
a book for wages and salaries for CB to
make those entries to.
The next thing that I can do is to
specify a transaction reminder.
Not all of the time we will
know how we will make payments.
Maybe we make payments via card or
maybe we make payments via cash.
We do not know.
But if it is a case that you remember
now that you want to be reminded about a
transaction down the road,
maybe in the next 30 minutes,
maybe in the next two hours,
maybe in the next five days,
bi-weekly, you get the picture.
What I can do is to specify a reminder for
CB to check in with me so that I can be
able to go ahead and record that
transaction for it to be able to record that
transaction for me.
For example, can you remind me in the next two minutes if
I have made a payment for fuel expense via cash or card?
Of course, you can span
this across five days.
Let us say by the end of the week,
normally you go ahead and
get gas for your vehicle.
And normally you're indifferent between
paying for between cash or card.
You can always ask CB to check in
with you, send a reminder message,
and then you will be able
to follow up with you.
And then after you clarify,
after that follow up,
it makes that transaction post for you.
There we go.
So I'm sending this as a message to CB.
CB will be able to see the
message, create the reminder.
I'll ping in about two minutes to check in
whether you made a fuel payment via cash or card.
I just do two minutes just
for the sake of this demo.
In the meantime, while we wait, we can
always go ahead and request reports.
Of course, the MSME can be able to
request reports through WhatsApp.
Can you send me copies of my balance
sheet and my transaction ledger?
I can always say general ledger.
There we go.
Sending this across to CB.
CB will be able to see this message
and send me copies of those documents.
We can request up to 11 reports
within the transaction ledger.
So there we go.
It's sending a message.
So this is a copy of my balance sheet.
There we go.
And then, of course, this is
a copy of my GL register.
These are for all of the
transactions that I would have done.
For the sake of this, I'm showing you
the last set of transactions that we did.
This is 180,000 NCB transfer
for AI marketing system.
Remember that transaction that we did?
The office supplies the cash on hand.
It debited and credited those entries.
We're also seeing for miscellaneous expense
and NCB for the bi-weekly salary payments.
So those are there specifically.
You can request up to 11 different
documents through the chat,
and then it will be able to
send those documents for you.
Of course, if you're an accounting firm,
you'll be given your own dashboard.
You can be able to filter for whichever
specific client you're serving
and actually request the
reports, download the reports,
as they're always up to date, up to
the last message that CB handled
for any one of your specific clients.
You'll be able to go ahead
and pull those records,
circumventing the need for
doing the bookkeeping yourself.
You can be able to follow
through specifically with that.
I'm going to be waiting
on the next two minutes.
It should be less than one minute
remaining for that message to come in.
There we go. It just came in.
Have you made a fuel payment recently?
Please let me know if it
was made by a cash or card.
I made the payment $9,000.
I should say 9K cash sending this.
I didn't specify the vendor, but
I'll go ahead and specify that.
CB will be able to see that
message and make that entry.
It made it via a miscellaneous expense.
Of course, because of the fact that
there is no dedicated fuel expense,
what we're expecting is that it will make
that payment via miscellaneous expense.
As stated before, if it is the case
that you're an accounting firm
and you want to make a dedicated
entry for fuel expense,
you can for your clients.
We're going to go ahead and
request updated transaction sheet.
Send it to me.
Sending that message across to CB so that you
can be able to see that entry that it made.
Of course, if you're an accounting
firm, you'll be able to go inside,
see that specific payment and
understand the description of it
so that for your own analytics or when you want
to go back through the actions that CB did,
it can always read those descriptions via
the description in the transaction ledger,
in the general ledger.
Fuel payment, $9,000 in cash,
no dedicated fuel expense.
Accounting COA posted to
miscellaneous expense.
Vendor not specified by owner.
Let us say for month one,
you're looking at this and you want
to create a specific fuel expense,
you can create it.
Or if you're already
working with this customer,
you already hand the
transactions for them,
and you know this is a typical
transaction that they do,
you can create that entry in
the chart of accounts for them.
So that is exactly how CB works.
You can be able to specify a transaction via
text, via voice note message, via an image,
or you can set reminders, and of course,
you can request up to 11 reports
directly within the chart.
And that is exactly how CB
works for your accounting firm.
Of course, you can see here where
it could be able to save you time
and, of course, help make
processes flow much more efficient.
That being said, if you are
interested in reaching out to us,
you can visit our website
at www.caribnexusai.com.
You can view our specific page,
caribnexusai.com/services/caribbooks.
You can also send us a WhatsApp
message at the number 1-876-770-6900.
And you can reach out to us
on Instagram @caribnexus_ai.
And you can also reach out
to us on LinkedIn as well.
With that said, thank you again for
taking the time to look at this video.
Have yourself a wonderful day.